{"test_questions": [[{"question": "What is a varistor?", "opta": "a voltage-dependent resistor", "optb": "a voltage-dependent diode", "optc": "a current-dependent resistor", "optd": "a current-dependent diode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of transformer is required to create a 180 degree input to a rectifier?", "opta": "center-tapped secondary", "optb": "step-down secondary", "optc": "stepped-up secondary", "optd": "split winding primary", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What circuit activity may shift a characteristic curve so that diode operating points are different?", "opta": "higher power (heat)", "optb": "higher resistance", "optc": "lower voltage", "optd": "lower current", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong with this diode?", "opta": "open", "optb": "short", "optc": "nothing", "optd": "not enough data", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The dc current through each diode in a bridge rectifier equals:", "opta": "the load current", "optb": "half the dc load current", "optc": "twice the dc load current", "optd": "one-fourth the dc load current", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When matching polarity connections have been made and the potential difference (PD) is above 0.7 V, the diode is considered to be:", "opta": "not working", "optb": "forward biased", "optc": "reverse biased", "optd": "an open switch", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a power supply diagram, which block indicates a smooth dc output?", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "rectifier", "optd": "regulator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 169.7 V half-wave peak has an average voltage of 54 V, what is the average of two full-wave peaks?", "opta": "119.9 V", "optb": "108.0 V", "optc": "115.7 V", "optd": "339.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the LED?", "opta": "0 mA", "optb": "23 mA", "optc": "18 mA", "optd": "13 mA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The characteristic curve for the complex model of a silicon diode shows that", "opta": "the barrier potential is 0 V", "optb": "the barrier potential stays fixed at 0.7 V", "optc": "the barrier potential increases slightly with an increase in current", "optd": "the barrier potential decreases slightly with an increase in current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Since diodes are destroyed by excessive current, circuits must have:", "opta": "higher voltage sources", "optb": "current limiting resistors", "optc": "more dopants", "optd": "higher current sources", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A diode for which you can change the reverse bias, and thus vary the capacitance is called a", "opta": "varactor diode", "optb": "tunnel diode", "optc": "zener diode", "optd": "switching diode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A filtered full-wave rectifier voltage has a smaller ripple than does a half-wave rectifier voltage for the same load resistance and capacitor values because:", "opta": "there is a shorter time between peaks", "optb": "there is a longer time between peaks", "optc": "the larger the ripple, the better the filtering action", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Testing a good diode with an ohmmeter should indicate", "opta": "high resistance when forward or reverse biased", "optb": "low resistance when forward or reverse biased", "optc": "high resistance when reverse biased and low resistance when forward biased", "optd": "high resistance when forward biased and low resistance when reverse biased", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The peak inverse voltage (PIV) across a nonconducting diode in a bridge rectifier equals approximately:", "opta": "half the peak secondary voltage", "optb": "twice the peak secondary voltage", "optc": "the peak value of the secondary voltage", "optd": "four times the peak value of the secondary voltage", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the diode?", "opta": "1 mA", "optb": "0.975 mA", "optc": "0.942 mA", "optd": "0.0 mA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electrons in the outermost orbit or shell of an atom are called", "opta": "free electrons", "optb": "negative ions", "optc": "valence electrons", "optd": "conduction band electrons", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Shunting the ac component away from the load is the task of a:", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "regulator", "optd": "rectifier", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A pn junction allows current flow when", "opta": "the p-type material is more positive than the n-type material", "optb": "the n-type material is more positive than the p-type material", "optc": "both the n-type and p-type materials have the same potential", "optd": "there is no potential on the n-type or p-type materials", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the current through the zener diode?", "opta": "0 mA", "optb": "7 mA", "optc": "8.3 mA", "optd": "13 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a diode is forward biased, the voltage across it", "opta": "is directly proportional to the current", "optb": "is inversely proportional to the current", "optc": "is directly proportional to the source voltage", "optd": "remains approximately the same", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is heat produced in a diode?", "opta": "due to current passing through the diode", "optb": "due to voltage across the diode", "optc": "due to the power rating of the diode", "optd": "due to the PN junction of the diode", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The arrow in the schematic symbol of a diode points to", "opta": "the n-type material, which is called the anode", "optb": "the n-type material, which is called the cathode", "optc": "the p-type material, which is called the anode", "optd": "the p-type material, which is called the cathode", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The diode schematic arrow points to the:", "opta": "trivalent-doped material", "optb": "positive axial lead", "optc": "anode lead", "optd": "cathode lead", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When checking a diode, low resistance readings both ways indicate the diode is:", "opta": "open", "optb": "satisfactory", "optc": "faulty", "optd": "not the problem", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a diode schematic, the anode is represented by a(n):", "opta": "triangle", "optb": "vertical line", "optc": "zig-zag line", "optd": "element indicator", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An IC regulator receives an overload; it will:", "opta": "shut down", "optb": "compensate for heat", "optc": "provide more voltage", "optd": "sample and adjust", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With full-wave rectification, current through the load resistor must be:", "opta": "in opposite directions", "optb": "to the external load", "optc": "from the reverse biased diode", "optd": "in the same direction", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A characteristic curve is the result of a current versus voltage plot of diode activity, which begins at the:", "opta": "3rd quadrant", "optb": "current plot", "optc": "graph origin", "optd": "voltage plot", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rectifier output polarity depends upon:", "opta": "cycles of input", "optb": "capacitor polarity", "optc": "half or full wave", "optd": "diode installation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a 12 V supply, a silicon diode, and a 370-ohm resistor in series, what voltage will be dropped across the diode?", "opta": "0.3 V", "optb": "0.7 V", "optc": "0.9 V", "optd": "1.4 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the frequency of the applied ac signal to a half-wave rectifier is 60 Hz, the frequency of the pulsating dc output will be", "opta": "30 pps", "optb": "60 pps", "optc": "90 pps", "optd": "120 pps", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the peak output voltage for this half-wave rectifier?", "opta": "1 V", "optb": "7.8 V", "optc": "10.9 V", "optd": "15.6 V", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thermal shutdown occurs in an IC regulator if:", "opta": "power dissipation is too high", "optb": "internal temperature is too high", "optc": "current through the device is too high", "optd": "load resistance increases", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The conduction band is closest to the valence band in", "opta": "semiconductors", "optb": "conductors", "optc": "insulators", "optd": "The distance is the same for all of the above.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the percent of regulation if Vnl = 20 V and Vfl = 19.8 V?", "opta": "0%", "optb": "1%", "optc": ".1%", "optd": "5%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a half-wave rectified voltage across the load resistor, load current flows for what part of a cycle?", "opta": "0 degrees", "optb": "90 degrees", "optc": "180 degrees", "optd": "360 degrees", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following circuits would require the least amount of filtering?", "opta": "A half-wave rectifier", "optb": "A full-wave rectifier", "optc": "A bridge rectifier", "optd": "A full-wave rectifier and a bridge rectifier", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is wrong with this circuit?", "opta": "The zener is open.", "optb": "The zener is shorted.", "optc": "nothing", "optd": "not enough data", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltage where current may start to flow in a reverse-biased pn junction is called the", "opta": "breakdown voltage", "optb": "barrier potential", "optc": "forward voltage", "optd": "biasing voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Providing a constant output regardless of ac input or load resistance changes is the function of a:", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "regulator", "optd": "rectifier", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a diode is destroyed it has infinite impedance. When damaged by heat it will probably:", "opta": "short", "optb": "conduct more", "optc": "conduct less", "optd": "open", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The area at the junction of p-type and n-type materials that has lost its majority carriers is called the", "opta": "barrier potential", "optb": "depletion region", "optc": "n region", "optd": "p region", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DC power should be connected to forward bias a diode as follows:", "opta": "\u2013 anode, + cathode", "optb": "\u2013 cathode, \u2013 anode", "optc": "+ anode, \u2013 cathode", "optd": "+ cathode, + anode", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "At any given time in an intrinsic piece of semiconductor material at room temperature", "opta": "electrons drift randomly", "optb": "recombination occurs", "optc": "holes are created", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a power supply diagram, which block indicates a pulsating dc output?", "opta": "transformer", "optb": "filter", "optc": "rectifier", "optd": "regulator", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List three diode packages:", "opta": "clip package, DIP, small current package", "optb": "DIP, small current package, large current package", "optc": "small current package, large current package, and SIP", "optd": "small current package, large current package, clip package", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mimicking of an open/closed switch by a diode allows alternating current to be:", "opta": "rectified", "optb": "regulated", "optc": "controlled", "optd": "attenuated", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}